Sara Coren Web Developer

CONTACT

610.772.1279

sara.coren@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/saracoren

https://github.com/saracoren

https://saracoren.github.io/ Portfolio

SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery, AJAX, APIs, Mongo, Materialize, Bootstrap, Heroku, Ruby on Rails, SQL, React, GitHub, Illustrator, Adobe XD, ArcGIS

EDUCATION

Certificate of Completion, Software Engineering **General Assembly**

Masters in General and Special Education (Gr. 1-6)

Touro College

Masters in Geography and Environmental Science University College London

Bachelors in Geology with a Minor in Sociology

The College of William & Mary

INTERESTS

UX Design, Innovation, Traveling, Hiking, Kayaking, Volunteering, Cross-Stitching

PROFILE

I am a product driven full stack web developer excited about expanding my knowledge base in the field. I have been a life-long learner and elementary educator as well as a researcher, geoscientist and humanitarian. I am passionate about using my web development skills and human centered approach in design to help people around the world access information to improve the quality of their lives.

EXPERIENCE

answerYES Consulting | Software Development Intern June 2019 - Present Stamford, Connecticut

- Currently working on a project to redo a WordPress website for a non-profit organization helping underserved kids in the Bridgeport community
- Gaining a lot of hands on experience with WP plugins, Adobe XD, Dreamweaver, information architecture, site mapping, theme selection and design

General Assembly | Software Engineering Immersive March 2019 - June 2019 Stamford, Connecticut

- Learned full stack web development with a variety of different technologies
- Created a number of web applications including a book list tracker for students
 using the Google Books API, a site where members can post information around
 the topic of innovation, an app to track experiences individuals want to check off
 of their bucket lists, and a site where users can post local events in the community
 using the Google Maps API

Various Schools | Lead Elementary Teacher and Math Coach August 2015 - June 2018 Northeastern Connecticut

- Wrote original curriculum and developed project based science lessons, activities and projects to help students connect their learning to the real world
- Worked as a math coach serving students in Grades K-5 with instructional support and providing data collection
- Substitute taught in various STEM classrooms in grades pre-K to 8

New York City Dept. of Education | Grade 4 Lead Teacher August 2010 - June 2015 New York, New York

- Worked in a small coaching group for Literacy Coaches with Columbia Teachers College staff developers
- Served as president of the School Leadership Team and gave professional development presentations to staff

United Nations | International Strategy for Disaster Reduction June 2008 - August 2008 Geneva, Switzerland

- Worked with an international team as an Information Management Unit Intern and attended the International Disaster and Risk Conference
- Conducted interviews with over 200 participants from a variety of backgrounds including government, academia, non-profit, industrial, etc. in order to reveal networks of people working together within the disaster community